# Erick Patiño Jaimes

# MECHATRONIC ENGINEER FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

Mechanical Design:

SolidWorks Fusion 360

Electronic Design:

Altium Eagle

Programing:

MySQL Postgres
Python HTML5
CSS3 JavaScript
React Tailwind
Sequalize Git
Github Express
Node C

# **LANGUAGES**

Spanish English Native

Intermediate-Advanced

# **SOFT SKILLS**

Responsible Adaptability Attention to detail Problem solving Creative Collaborative Committed

TODICITI SOLVILIE

# **CONTACT DETAILS**

Email: <u>pj\_erick@hotmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/erick-patiño-ba7a8216a

Mobile: (+52) 55 12 02 69 02 GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/EPJHUB">https://github.com/EPJHUB</a>

Portfolio: <a href="https://portafolio-delta-gray.vercel.app">https://portafolio-delta-gray.vercel.app</a>

### **ABOUT ME**

Energetic and passionate college graduate with a Bachelor of Science in Mechatronics Engineering, self-taught and enthusiastic for learning and enhancing the knowledge and skills I've acquire during my professional career. Creativity and hardworking are skills that defines me as engineer. Aiming to collaborate in areas such as software development, both mechanical and electric design and automation. Excited about using my expertise and tenacity to grow in the industry.

# **EDUCATION**

Full-stack developer

September 2023 – March 2024 Mexico City, Mexico

Academio

August 2014 – December 2019

IPN – UPIITA

Mexico City, Mexico

Digital Systems Technician IPN - CECYT 9 "Juan de Dios Bátiz"

**B.S. Mechatronics Engineering** 

August 2010 – December 2013

Mexico City, Mexico

# **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

# Mechatronics Engineer-Innovatecsi.

August 2021 - Present

### CDMX, México

- Design and implementation of devices for care and monitoring of contact sports athletes in order to prevent concussions with the help of microsensors.
- Programming of microcontrollers focused on radio frequencies and the Internet of Things, for the processing and transmission of data through a wireless network.
- Design and implementation of test boards, radio frequency transmitters and receivers, control boards, as well as the management of electronic component libraries to improve workflow and reduce project development time.
- Development of technical documentation (manufacturing and assembly diagrams, user manuals, connection diagrams, etc.) for compliance with Norma Oficial Mexicana NOM-241-SSA1-2021.
- Implementation of communication protocols for embedded systems.
- Design and implementation of Captive Portal (HTML, CSS and Javascript) for IoT devices configuration.

# Integration Engineer-Ericsson Telecom S.A. de C.V.

November 2020 - April 2021

- Integration of new technologies (5G and 4G), remotely reconfiguration and updating of networks
- Collaboration and coordination with international teams to perform reconfiguration and integration activities.
- KPI's inspection to ensure compliance with costumer's expectations, as well as the preparation of reports before and after integration and update activities.

# **CERTIFICATES**

- Coursera Google IT Automation with Python
- Project management and other tools for career development
- English B2 CELEX UPIICSA IPN
- Academio Fundamentals HTML, CSS y Javascript
- Academio Front-end development with React

### **PROJECTS**

# **Graduation Project: Automatic Vertical Orchard HVA**

- Design and implementation of control boards (Altium).
- Design and machining of tools for HVA (SolidWorks, Mastercam X5)